eftours.com 2003-06-18

# Privacy

|  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |  |   
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
  
---|---|---|---|---|---  
  
|  |   
---|---|---  
  
|   
---  
<< Return to Previous Page  
Our Commitment to Your Privacy  
The privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for www.eftours.com. If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should contact our [Webmaster](mailto:webmaster@eftours.com) by email. 

EF Tours is committed to protecting the privacy of our online users. We would like to share our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, it is available in the navigation bar at the bottom of every page and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested. This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the eftours.com website.

|   
  
We also participate in the Council of Better Business Bureaus' BBBOnLine® Reliability Program, and comply with all the [BBBOnLine](http://www.bbbonline.org/) privacy standards. 

Our Commitment to Children's Privacy  
Protecting the privacy of children is especially important. For that reason, we require parental consent from users under 18 who wish to make a reservation. A child's personal information will be used to complete a reservation but it will not be used in circumstances outside of what is required to operate the business or site.  
Collection of Personal Information  
On our site, you can order products and materials, make payments on your account, and sign up to lead or travel on a tour. EFTours.com maintains the confidentiality, security, and integrity of personal information that we obtain from our users. We limit the personally identifiable information we collect to only that which is required to participate on an EF Tour. This includes your name, address, email address, phone number, date of birth, emergency contact information, and financial data such as credit/debit card and/or checking account numbers. 

When visiting other websites linked from eftours.com, submitting personally identifiable information is subject to that site's privacy policies. This applies to any external links from our site. We encourage users to check for privacy policies of any sites that collect personally identifiable information. 

When you send a digital postcard, refer a teacher, or use the "tell a friend" to describe a particular tour, we ask for the recipient's name and email address. 

|   
Collection of Non Personal Information  
We collect site traffic data from cookie usage on our site. We also use information about IP addresses, types of Web browsers, Internet Service Providers (ISPs), referring and exit pages, operating systems, date/time stamps, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track users' movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses and the like are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

We also keep track of search terms, so we know what visitors to our site are looking for. We do this so that we may better develop the site to meet the needs of our users.   
  
The Way We Use Information  
We use the information you provide about yourself when placing an order, only to complete that order. We are required to collect this information in order to complete your travel documents. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete your reservation. 

Personal information collected by EFTours.com is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public. However, should you provide personally identifiable information through email exchanges. We will protect your privacy to the best of our ability by monitoring the sessions, but always keep in mind that when you are in a public forum, you control the information you disclose. You should always be careful when distributing your personal information in this manner. 

We use the information you provide about someone else only to confirm message delivery for the 'refer a teacher' or 'email a page' function. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to confirm that message. Information you provide to us to create a message is only used for that purpose, and it is only disclosed to the recipient. 

We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties. 

You can indicate that you would like to receive our catalog, our e-kits, as well as updates on our new products and services. Information you submit on our website will not be used for these purposes unless you request these services. To respect the privacy of our users, we provide the opportunity to opt-out of types of communications. If you would like to be removed from the mailing list please email [webmaster@eftours.com](mailto:webmaster@eftours.com)

While applying for contests online, you will be able to indicate whether or not you wish to receive promotional emails. You may remove your email address from our mailing list at any time by contacting us at [webmaster@eftours.com](mailto:webmaster@eftours.com) or (800) 637-8222. 

EFTours.com may provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and related site information to reputable third-party vendors, but these statistics will include no personally identifying information. 

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifying information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.   
  
Our Commitment To Data Security  
We exercise great care in providing secure transmission of our users' financial information from their computers to our servers by using encryption technology. We use secure online forms and store all information in protected operating environments inaccessible to the public.  |  [](https://digitalid.verisign.com/as2/b5fc39afcc4a6e2ce95adaa3bcc69507)  
Use of "Cookies"  
"Cookies" are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We use both session and persistent cookies. The use of cookies is an industry standard, used to provide useful features for customers. Cookies by themselves, do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user's computer. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that. If you do so, however, you may not be able to take full advantage of our website. For example, the complete online reservation process can only be accessed if you accept cookies. Currently, we do not tie cookie usage to personally identifiable information.   
Reviewing or Changing Your Information  
You can access personal information online by providing your customer number and password when prompted at the login. We use this procedure to better safeguard your information. 

You can correct the majority of factual errors in your personal account directly online up to your final payment date. You can request these changes via email at [webmaster@eftours.com](mailto:webmaster@eftours.com), by calling our toll-free number at (800) 637-8222, or by sending mail to: 

EF Educational Tours  
One Education Street  
Cambridge, MA 02141 

To delete or deactivate your account, please call (800) 637-8222 

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.   
  
Your Consent  
By using our website, you consent to the collection and use of this information by EFTours.com. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post any changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. If we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of email. If, however, you have opted out of communication with the site then you will not be contacted, nor will your personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes to our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our website notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post the notice we will also email users who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.   
Tell Us What You Think  
EFTours.com welcomes your questions and comments about privacy. Should you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policies, please call us at 1-800-637-8222 or send us an email at [webmaster@eftours.com](mailto:webmaster@eftours.com).  
<< Return to Previous Page
